onkyo.com 2019-08-25

# ONKYO PRIVACY STATEMENT | ONKYO

Last Updated: [Feb 26, 2019]

## ONKYO GROUP PRIVACY STATEMENT

At the Onkyo Group Companies, including but not limited to, Onkyo Corporation, Onkyo & Pioneer Corporation, Pioneer & Onkyo USA corporation and Pioneer & Onkyo Europe GmbH (collectively, “Company” or “we/our/us”), we are dedicated to protecting your privacy and safeguarding your personally identifiable information. Company's mission is to consistently exceed our customers' expectations in terms of the products and services we provide to our customers. We strive to create an experience that is responsive to our customers' needs by using the information you entrust us with responsibly. Company is committed to respecting your privacy and adhering to the principles of applicable data protection and privacy laws throughout the world. For the purposes of the Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (General Data Protection Regulation – “GDPR”) in the current version Onkyo & Pioneer Corporation is the data controller.

We have provided this Privacy Statement as an explanation of the information we collect, how we use it, how the use of this information can benefit your experience on our web sites and during your relationship with us, with whom and for what purposes we may share the information, and the choices you can make about our use of the information. We also describe the measures we take to protect the security of the information and how you can contact us about our privacy practices. Our privacy practices may vary among the countries in which we operate to reflect local practices and legal requirements. We wish to help you make informed decisions, so please take a moment to read the sections below.

**COMPANY WEBSITES AND PRODUCTS:**

In order to provide multiple access points to the services and products we offer, Company operates directly, or through its subsidiaries, affiliates or other business partners, several web sites, including but not limited to www.onkyo.com, www.pioneer-audiovisual.com, and http://www.jp.onkyo.com/. Any one of these Company group web sites may ask for and collect personally identifiable information in order to enhance your experience and provide you with relevant information. Local Privacy Policies may vary from this Privacy Statement and as they are more specific, they prevail with regard to the respective website as linked thereto. 

Company designs, manufactures, and sells as well as has designed, made and sold its products (“Products”) with those brands which Company owns, is contractually licensed to use, or licenses to have used (collectively “Company Brands”) or similar company or brand logo(s) and trademark(s) in relation with Company Brands. Through the possession or the use of such Products, Company may ask for and collect personally identifiable information in order to enhance your experience and provide you with relevant information.

This Privacy Statement governs your use of any online service location (e.g., web site or mobile app) that posts a link to this Privacy Statement (each a “Site”) (including, without limitation, both mobile and online versions, and also applies to your use of interactive features, widgets, plug-ins, applications, content, downloads and/or other services that we own and control and make available through a Site and/or that posts a link to this Privacy Statement (collectively, the “Service”), regardless of how you access or use them, whether via personal computers, Products, mobile devices or otherwise.

**TYPES OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT**  
Company collects information about our customers on the Service so that we can provide the Product or an experience that is responsive to our customers' needs and desire. Information may be collected as part of (i) use of the Products through the Internet, (ii) customer registration, (iii) shopping through one of the Company group sites, (iv) submitting a job application, (v) responding to communications from us (e.g., surveys, promotional offers, or various SNS apps), (vi) working with third party sources, including collecting publicly available information from social networking web sites, to better assist us with understanding your interests and to serve you better, (vii) your use of our apps on your electronic devices, (viii) updating the software of your unit of the Products, (ix) modifying the registered information including but not limited to your address which Company lawfully and appropriately received and maintained upon your request. The types of personally identifiable information, which is information that identifies you personally, (sometimes referred to as “PII”) that we collect may include but not limited to your name, home, work and e-mail addresses, telephone, mobile telephone, and fax numbers, credit card information, date of birth, gender, and other information necessary to fulfill special requests. In addition, we may collect demographic information, such as information about your gender, income, education level, and occupation (“Demographic Information”). To the extent we combine Demographic Information with your PII we collect directly from you on the Service, we will treat the combined data as PII under this Privacy Statement. If you access the Company group websites under applicability of the GDPR, we will only collect personal data based on your consent, a contractual obligation, statutory provisions or legitimate interests after informing you comprehensively regarding the purpose of the collecting and processing of the specific personal data collected or processed. Personal data in the meaning of the GDPR means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (‘data subject’). For clarification purposes and where the GDPR is applicable, this Privacy Statement uses the term “PII”, however, the definition of personal information of the GDPR will prevail for in case of doubt. 

In addition to any PII or other information that you choose to submit to us via our Service, we and our third-party service providers may use a variety of technologies that automatically (or passively) store or collect certain information whenever you visit or interact with the Service (“Usage Information”). For clarification, where GDPR is applicable, Usage Information is personal information. This Usage Information may be stored or accessed using a variety of technologies that may be downloaded to your personal computer, browser, laptop, tablet, mobile phone, Product or other device (a “Device”) whenever you visit or interact with our Service. To the extent we associate Usage Information with your PII we collect directly from you on the Service, we will treat it as PII. For clarification, where GDPR is applicable, Usage Information is personal information. This Usage Information may include: (i) your IP address, UDID or other unique identifier (“Device Identifier”). A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your Device used to access the Service, and our computers identify your Device by its Device Identifier; (ii) your Device functionality (including browser, operating system, hardware, mobile network information); (iii) the URL that referred you to our Service; (iv) the areas within our Service that you visit and your activities there, including remembering you and your preferences; (v) your Device location; (vi) your Device characteristics; and (vii) certain other Device data, including the time of day and log information indicating conditions of Product, among other information.

**PURPOSE FOR COLLECTION, PROCESSING, AND DISCLOSURE**  
[Purpose for Collection]  
Company is fully committed to providing you with information about the collection and use of PII furnished by, or collected from, our customers while using our Service and Products. It is our practice not to ask you for information unless we need it or intend to use it. Some of the primary purposes for collecting your PII are as follows: (i) providing services such as processing certain transactions (e.g., processing your purchases on our Services, fulfilling a request for information, or completing a product order); (ii) marketing and communications with you in relation to the Products and Services offered by Company, our strategic marketing partners, and other trusted third parties; (iii) performing market research via surveys and analysis of customers’ opinion to better serve your needs, improve the effectiveness of our Services and Products, your experience with our Products and Services; (iv) our various types of communications, advertising campaigns, and/or promotional activities; (v) for internal business purposes; and (vi) for purposes disclosed at the time you provide your information or as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Statement.

You may choose to receive marketing emails and Company surveys. Please note that you may opt out of marketing emails and Company surveys at any time by contacting us directly to opt out of direct marketing, telemarketing, emails or surveys. Whenever necessary, you will be offered the choice not to submit your PII or to decide what communications you want to receive from us. However, doing so may cause certain transactions to become affected.

Interest-Based Advertising and Location-Based Services. As further set forth below, we may also use your PII, Demographic Information or Usage Information that we collect about you: (1) to specifically target relevant advertisements or content to you based on how you interact with our Services; (2) to understand the usefulness to you of the advertisements or content that have been delivered to you; and (3) to increase our Services profile, including allowing you to comment or add content to the Services.

Use of Information for Recruitment Purposes. Where you have provided us with PII or Demographic Information as part of an online application for employment or internship, we may use that information in order to allow us to make an informed decision about whether to proceed with your application. We may, as part of this recruitment process, collect information about your education, employment history and similar matters. Where this PII or Demographic Information is considered to be sensitive, you expressly consent to our processing of this information for recruitment purposes by submitting it to us.

Posting Your Comments When you post your comment or opinion to Company group websites, you may in your choice disclose your PII or other information with your comment. If you willingly disclose such sensitive information in or with your comment, you expressly consent that such information may be disclosed by Company for this purpose. The Company Privacy Statement remains applicable.

Processing and Disclosure  
In most cases, the information you provide is added to a local or global database. In the course of processing your information, it may be necessary to transfer your PII to Company's affiliates, properties within the Company system and/or third party service providers located in Japan and throughout the world for the purposes outlined within this Privacy Statement. Unless otherwise precluded or governed by legal requirements and/or process, Company, its subsidiaries and its affiliates that may receive your information are required to abide by substantially similar privacy requirements relating to your PII. As a general practice, Company does not sell, rent, or give physical possession of your PII to unaffiliated third parties outside the Company system. For international transfer of personal data, we apply the standards of GDPR as described below under “DATA TRANSFERS ACROSS INTERNATIONAL BORDERS". 

Situations in which Company may disclose your information to others include: (i) when we have received your consent to do so in situations where sharing or disclosing your information is required in order to offer you products or services you desire; (ii) when companies or services providers are performing business activities on behalf of Company (e.g., credit card processing, customer support services, market research administration or database management services), (iii) to a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of the Service or applicable database; or in connection with a merger, consolidation, restructuring, the sale of substantially all of our interests and/or assets or other corporate change, including, during the course of any due diligence process; (iv) to comply with legal or regulatory requirements or obligations in accordance with applicable law, a court order or a subpoena; (v) in case of emergency such as to safeguard the life, health, or property of an individual; (vi) to deliver social content and advertising; and (vii) in connection with sweepstakes, contests and promotions that you may sign up for, including the posting of winner’s list, prize fulfillment, and as required by law. We may share non-PII, such as aggregated user statistics, with third parties. We may share your Device Identifiers with third parties along with data related to you and your activities.

If information is shared as mentioned above, we seek to limit the scope of information that is furnished to the amount necessary for the performance of the specific function. Unless otherwise precluded by legal process, we require third parties to protect your PII and abide by applicable privacy laws and regulations.

**CONSENT**  
Whenever you expressly give your consent, as part of our commitment to keep you informed, we may mail, e-mail, telephone, or contact you by other means to notify you of new Products and services, or upcoming Company special offers, events, enhancements, or other relevant information that may be of interest to you. You may also receive mailings or other communications from carefully selected third parties. We offer you the option to decline any or all of these Company communications by following the directions included in our e-mails or other communications, or by contacting Company directly.

We would like to keep all of our customers informed and equally able to take advantage of the benefits offered by Company and its strategic marketing partners. However, if you reside outside of Japan, certain data privacy regulations may require us to obtain your permission before we send you information that you have not requested from us.

In addition, the legal basis for processing your personal information may also be the contract concluded between you and Company or legitimate interest. Such cases may be the use of the Products and services as well as the nature of the service requested or transaction undertaken. In addition, your permission will be deemed given for communications from us that are necessary to fulfill transactions and services that you request. Please note that we reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to your account or use of our Service, such as administrative and service announcements, and these transactional account messages may be unaffected if you choose to opt-out from receiving our marketing communications.

You may object to Company disclosing your PII with third parties except when: (i) service providers have been retained to perform services on behalf of Company; (ii) disclosure is required by law; (iii) disclosure concerns national, legal or public interest grounds; (iv) disclosure is necessary to protect the interests of Company or third parties; (v) information has been collected from publicly accessible sources; (vi) disclosure concerns the retrospective processing of the information for historical, statistical or enhancement of user experiences; (vii) disclosure is authorized by a supervisory authority (such as a Privacy Commissioner, Data Protection Authority, or other similar authority); or (viii) is otherwise permitted in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

**DATA TRANSFERS ACROSS INTERNATIONAL BORDERS**  
As a global company, we endeavor to provide you with the highest quality of the Products and services anywhere in the world. To achieve this goal, we have established a global network comprised of properties, offices, data centers, trusted marketing partners, service providers, customer contact centers, and trained associates around the globe. The nature of our business and our operations require us to transfer your information, including PII, to other group companies, properties, centers of operations, data centers, or service providers that may be located in countries outside of your own. We may transfer the PII we collect about you to countries other than the country in which the information was originally collected. Although the data protection and other laws of these various countries may not be as comprehensive as those in your own country, Company will take appropriate steps to ensure that your PII is protected and handled as described in this Privacy Statement. 

If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that information we collect, including PII, may be transferred to, and processed, stored and used in the United States. The data protection laws in the United States may differ from those of the country in which you are located, and your PII may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in the United States according to laws of the United States. By using the Service or providing us with any information, you consent to the transfer to, and processing, usage, sharing and storage of your information, including PII, in the United States as set forth in this Privacy Statement.

In order to process your personal data for the purposes set out in this privacy policy, we may transfer your personal data to third parties and other companies in our group which are based outside of the EU and EEA (”Europe”). To ensure that your personal data is secure, we will only transfer your information to countries outside of Europe where we do so in accordance with the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (”GDPR”). This requires that one of the following conditions applies:

* the European Commission has decided that the country provides an adequate level of protection for your personal data (in accordance with Article 45 of the GDPR);
* the transfer is subject to a legally binding and enforceable commitment on the recipient to protect the personal data (in accordance with Article 46 of the GDPR);
* the transfer is made subject to binding corporate rules (in accordance with Article 47 of the GDPR); or
* the transfer is based on a derogation from the GDPR restrictions on transferring personal data outside of the EU (in accordance with Article 49).

**YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**  
Under California law, California residents who have an established business relationship with Company or one of its subsidiaries may choose to opt out of Company’s disclosure of personal information about them to third parties for direct marketing purposes. Unless noted at the time of collection, our policy is not to disclose personal information collected online to a third party for direct marketing purposes without your approval. If you choose to opt-out at any time after granting approval, email http://www.onkyousa.com/Support/#EMAILUS or write to Company at Onkyo U.S.A. Corporation, 18 Park Way, Upper Saddle River, New Jersey 07458, USA, Attn: CA Privacy Rights.

**YOUR ADDITIONAL EUROPEAN PRIVACY RIGHTS.**  
If you are a resident of a Member State of the European Union or the European Economic Area you have the right to access, right to rectification, right to erasure, right to restriction of processing, right to data portability and right to object to the processing of your personal data. We will inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your before mentioned rights to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise your rights at any time by contacting us in the following ways: Postal Mail: Pioneer & Onkyo Europe GmbH  
Gutenbergstraße 3, D-82178 Puchheim, Germany  
If you have reason to complain, you can also contact a supervisory authority. The supervisory authority primarily responsible for us is: Bayerisches Landesamt für Datenschutzaufsicht (BayLDA), Promenade 27, 91522 Ansbach,   
Telephone: +49 (0) 981 53 1300,   
Fax: +49 (0) 981 53 98 1300,  
poststelle@lda.bayern.de.  
The criteria used to determine the period of storage of personal data is the respective statutory retention period. After expiration of that period, the corresponding data is routinely deleted, as long as it is no longer necessary for the fulfillment of the contract or the initiation of a contract.  
As a responsible company, we do not use automatic decision-making or profiling.

**ON-LINE TECHNOLOGIES**  
We are giving you detailed notice of the Tracking Technologies (as defined below) and your limited choices regarding them so that your consent is meaningfully informed.

Company and its third party marketing partners may use cookies, invisible pixels, and web beacons to obtain information about you while visiting our Services (collectively, “Tracking Technologies”). A cookie is a very small text file that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your AV receiver's hard drive. Company cookies assign your AV receiver with a unique identifier, which in turn, becomes your identification card whenever you return to an Company web site.

Cookies are designed to save you time because they help us to provide you with a customized experience without you having to remind us of your preferences each time you return to our web pages. Company cookies are not designed to damage your files, nor can they read information from other files on your AV receiver hard drive.

Cookies can also help us provide you with a personalized on-line experience in the following ways:  
they remember your user name and password for future visits so log-in is easier and faster;  
they ensure you are provided with the appropriate frames and content.  
they ensure you obtain all requested information; and  
they help us deliver communications that are relevant and responsive to your interests and location. 

**Tracking Technologies Usage**.  We may use Tracking Technologies for a variety of purposes, including:  
**_Strictly Necessary_**. We may use cookies or other Tracking Technologies that we consider are strictly necessary to allow you to use and access our Service, including cookies required to prevent fraudulent activity, improve security or allow you to make use of shopping cart functionality.  
**_Performance‑Related_**. We may use cookies or other Tracking Technologies that are useful in order to assess the performance of the Service, including as part of our analytic practices or otherwise to improve the content, products or services offered through the Service.  
**_Functionality‑Related_**.We may use cookies or other Tracking Technologies that are required to offer you enhanced functionality when accessing the Service, including identifying you when you sign in to our Service or keeping track of our specified preferences, including in terms of the presentation of content on our Service.  
**_Targeting‑Related_**.  We may use Tracking Technologies to deliver content, including ads, relevant to your interests on our Service and third party sites based on how you interact with our advertisements or content. This includes using Tracking Technologies to understand the usefulness to you of the advertisements and content that have been delivered to you.

We track the usage of our web sites in order to better meet your needs and to help make it easier for you to find information in the future. Please note that in addition to Company cookies, various third parties may also place Tracking Technologies on your Device, which may include the collection of information about your online activities over time and across third-party web sites or online services. Company may not control these third party Tracking Technologies, and is not responsible for the presence or absence of third party Tracking Technologies, or for the technological capabilities or practices employed by third parties in connection with third party cookies. However, you consent to potentially encountering third party Tracking Technologies in connection with use of our Service and accept that our statements under this Privacy Statement do not apply to the Tracking Technologies or practices of such third parties.

If you would prefer not to have the benefits of cookies, your Internet browser can be adjusted to treat cookies in different ways. Depending upon the type of browser you are using, you may be able to configure your browser so that: (i) you are prompted to accept or reject cookies on an individual basis or (ii) you may be able to prevent your browser from accepting any cookies at all. You should refer to the supplier or manufacturer of your web browser for specific details about cookie security. However, you should also understand that rejecting cookies might affect your ability to perform certain transactions on our web sites and our ability to recognize your browser from one visit to the next. Each browser you use will need to be set separately and different browsers offer different functionality and options in this regard.

App-related Tracking Technologies in connection with non-browser usage (e.g., most functionality of the App) can only be disabled by uninstalling the App. To uninstall an App, follow the instructions from your operating system or handset manufacturer.

Company also uses invisible pixels, sometimes called web beacons, to count how many people visit certain web pages. Information collected from invisible pixels is used and reported in the aggregate and does not contain PII. Company may use this information to improve marketing programs and content.

**THIRD PARTY TRACKING AND DO NOT TRACK**  
We may also work with vendors and marketing partners to help deliver advertisements and personalized content that we believe will be of interest to you. These vendors and other partners include advertisers, advertising agencies, advertising networks, audience segment providers, data exchanges, analytics providers, and other similar providers. Please see the chart at the end of this policy for a current list of the agencies and providers with which we work. These partners and vendors may use Tracking Technologies to collect information about your online activity (e.g., the sites and pages you have visited at Company sites and other third party sites) in order to help Company (and in some cases, third party advertisers) deliver personalized content and advertising to you while you are on Company or other sites.

For example, if you go to a Company site to look at one of our Products, you may later see an advertisement from us when you visit another web site. We may also engage one of these vendors to deliver our advertisements to consumers whose online behaviors on sites other than the Company sites indicate that they may be interested in travel. In other instances, we engage in special arrangements with certain advertisers with which we think our web site visitors would have an interest. We allow these advertisers to deliver co-branded messages (e.g., Company and the advertiser) directly to consumers who have visited our web pages. These types of cobranded advertisements may appear on Company sites or on third party sites.

Your browser or other third party mechanisms may be able to allow you to signal or otherwise express your choice regarding the collection of information about your online activities over time and across third-party web sites or online services (e.g., browser do not track signals). Currently, we do not monitor or take any action with respect to these “do not track” signals or other mechanisms..

**INTERACTIONS WITH THIRD PARTY SERVICES AND LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES:**  
The Service may include functionality that allows certain kinds of interactions between the Service and a third-party web site or application. The use of this functionality may involve the third-party operator providing certain information, including Personal Information, to us. For example, when you register with the Service, you may have an option to use your Facebook, Google or other account provided by a third-party site or application to facilitate the registration and log-in or transaction process on the Service, or otherwise link accounts. If we offer and you choose to use this functionality to access or use our Service, the third-party site or application may send PII about you to us. If so, we will then treat it as PII under this Privacy Statement, since we are collecting it as a result of your accessing of and interaction on our Service. In addition, we may provide third-party sites’ interfaces or links on the Service to facilitate your sending a communication from the Service. For example, we may use third parties to facilitate emails, tweets or Facebook postings. These third parties may retain any information used or provided in any such communications or other activities and these third parties’ practices are not subject to our Privacy Statement. Company may not control or have access to your communications through these third parties. Further, when you use third-party sites or services, you are using their services and not our services and they, not we, are responsible for their practices. You should review the applicable third-party privacy policies before using such third-party tools on our Service.

In order to anticipate your needs, Company provides links to other web sites for your convenience and information. Company is not responsible or liable for any content presented by or contained on any independent web site, including, but not limited to, any advertising claims or marketing practices. Please note that while Company will take reasonable steps to protect your information on Company owned and operated web sites, we cannot control and will not be responsible for the privacy policies of third party web sites, including web sites owned or controlled by independent distributors that may use the name of a Company brand, or web sites or mobile applications not controlled or authorized by Company. Third party web sites that are accessed through links on our web sites have separate privacy and data collection practices, and security measures. We have no responsibility or liability for the practices, policies and security measures implemented by third parties on their web sites. We encourage you to contact them to ask questions about their privacy practices, policies and security measures before disclosing any PII. We recommend that you review the privacy statements and policies of linked web sites to understand how those web sites collect, use and store information.

Please note that the personal data collected will not be transferred to third parties unless otherwise stated. We will inform you in each case separately about the transfer of personal data to third parties. 

**MINORS**  
We are a general audience service and do not use the Service to knowingly collect PII from children under the age of thirteen (13) that requires parental notice and consent under the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) or other applicable law, without such parental consent. Company does not seek to obtain nor does it wish to receive PII directly from minors; however, we cannot always determine the age of persons who access and use our web sites. In the event that Company becomes aware that we have collected personal information from any child (as defined by applicable law), we will dispose of that information in accordance with COPPA and other applicable laws and regulations. If you are a parent or guardian and you believe that your child under the age of 13 has provided us with personal information without COPPA-required consent, we encourage the parent or guardian to contact us to have this information removed and to unsubscribe the minor from future Company marketing communications. If you are a child under 13 years of age, you are not permitted to use the Service and should not send any information about yourself to us through the Service.

For purpose of the GDPR and within its territorial scope (i.e. EU and EEA), please note that:  
In case the consent has given in relation to the offer of information society services directly to a child, the processing of the personal data of a child shall be lawful where the child is at least 16 years old. Where the child is below the age of 16 years, such processing shall be lawful only if and to the extent that consent is given or authorized by the holder of parental responsibility over the child. 

**CONTACT US:**  
Updating Your Communication Preferences

You are responsible for maintaining the accuracy of the information you submit to us, such as your contact information provided as part of registration. The Service may allow you to review, correct or update PII you have provided through the Service’s registration forms or otherwise. If you would like to update your information, modify your communication preferences, or if you do not want to receive marketing communications from Company in the future, you can contact us:

by e-mail: privacy.policy@jp.onkyo.com  
by writing to us at:  
Attn: Global CS Division Manager  
O&P Corporation  
2-1 Nisshin-cho, Neyagawa, Osaka 572 8540 JAPAN

If you have comments or questions regarding Company's data privacy practices or this Privacy Statement, you may contact us by choosing the most convenient method from the following:

by e-mail: privacy.policy@jp.onkyo.com  
by writing to us at:  
Attn: Global CS Division Manager  
O&P Corporation  
2-1 Nisshin-cho, Neyagawa, Osaka 572 8540 JAPAN

We will make good faith efforts to make requested changes in our then active databases as soon as reasonably practicable (but we may retain prior information as business records). With respect to our mobile and other applications (i.e., when we are the application publisher), you can prospectively stop all collection of information by the application by uninstalling the application. You may use the standard uninstall process as may be available as part of your applicable Device or potentially via the appropriate application or app marketplace. Please note that it is not always possible to completely remove or delete all of your information from our databases and that residual data may remain on backup media or for other reasons. When you edit your PII or change your preferences on the Service, information that you remove may persist internally for our administrative purposes.

**UPDATES TO THE PRIVACY STATEMENT:**  
Company may amend this Privacy Statement from time to time in order to meet changes in the regulatory environment, business needs, or to satisfy the needs of our customers. Updated versions will be posted to our web site and date stamped so that you are always aware of when the Privacy Statement was last updated. Any changes will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Statement and your use of our Service indicates your consent to the privacy statement posted at the time of use. However, we will not use your previously collected PII in a manner materially different than represented at the time it was collected without your consent. To the extent any provision of this Privacy Statement is found by a competent tribunal to be invalid or unenforceable, such provision shall be severed to the extent necessary for the remainder to be valid and enforceable.

## END OF ONKYO GROUP PRIVACY STATEMENT

The following third parties that collect information from you on or in connection with our Service have given us notice that you may obtain information on their policies and practices, and in some instances opt-out of certain of their activities, as follows:

We are not responsible for third-party policies or practices. We try to keep this information current, and will add to and subtract from the chart above as appropriate, but it is provided as a courtesy and may not be current or accurate. Please contact the applicable third parties regarding their privacy and data security policies and practices.
